<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verification on OWASP SAMM</title>
    <link>https://owaspsamm.org/business_functions/verification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Verification on OWASP SAMM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owaspsamm.org/business_functions/verification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Assessment</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/verification/v-architecture-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/verification/v-architecture-assessment/</guid>
      <description>Proposed Overview (updated objectives)     A: Architecture Validation B: Architecture Compliance     Maturity 1 - Review the architecture to ensure baseline mitigations are in place for known risks. Identify application and infrastructure architecture components Ad-hoc review of the architecture against compliance requirement   Maturity 2 - Review the complete provision of security mechanisms in the architecture Are the architecture security mechanisms well implemented Analyze the architecture against known security requirements and best practices   Maturity 3 - Review the architecture effectiveness and feedback results to improve the security architecture Review of the architecture components effectiveness Feedback the architecture review results into the enterprise architecture, organisation design principles &amp;amp; patterns, security solutions and reference architectures    Original Overview     A: Application Architecture B: Supporting Architecture     Maturity 1 - Support ad-hoc reviews of software design to ensure baseline mitigations for known risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements Driven Testing</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/verification/v-requirements-driven-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/verification/v-requirements-driven-testing/</guid>
      <description>Overview     A: Control Verification B: Misuse/Abuse Testing     Maturity 1 - Opportunistically find basic vulnerabilities and other security issues. Test for standard security controls Perform security fuzzing testing   Maturity 2 - Perform implementation review to discover application-specific risks against the security requirements. Derive test cases from known security requirements Create and test abuse cases and business logic flaw test   Maturity 3 - Maintain the application security level after bug fixes, changes or during maintenance Perform regression testing (with security unit tests) Denial of service and security stress testing    Overview A: Control Verification &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/verification/v-security-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/verification/v-security-testing/</guid>
      <description>Overview     A: Scalable Baseline B: Deep Understanding     Maturity 1 - Perform security testing (both manual and tool based) to discover security defects. Utilize automated security testing tools Perform manual security testing of high-risk components   Maturity 2 - Make security testing during development more complete and efficient through automation complemented with regular manual security penetration tests Employ application-specific security testing automation Conduct manual penetration testing   Maturity 3 - Embed security testing as part of the development and deployment processes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>