<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Operations on OWASP SAMM</title>
    <link>https://owaspsamm.org/business_functions/operations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Operations on OWASP SAMM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owaspsamm.org/business_functions/operations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Incident Management</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/operations/o-incident-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/operations/o-incident-management/</guid>
      <description>Overview     A: Incident Detection B: Incident Response     Maturity 1 - Best-effort incident detection and handling Best-effort incident detection with available log data Defined high-level incident response strategy   Maturity 2 - Formal incident management process in place Automated log evaluation driven by process Root Cause Analysis with feedback loop   Maturity 3 - Mature incident management Reliable timely incident detection Proactive incident + emergency exercises    A: Incident Detection Maturity 1 Activity On the first level, log data (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment Management</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/operations/o-environment-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/operations/o-environment-management/</guid>
      <description>Overview     A: Configuration Hardening B: Patching (and Updating)     Maturity 1 - Best-effort patching and hardening Prioritized best-effort hardening Prioritized best-effort patching   Maturity 2 - Formal process with baselines in place Hardening baseline and guidelines available Formal process covering the full stack   Maturity 3 - Conformity with continuously improving process enforced Detection and handling of non-conformities Consolidated update process with SLA and reporting    A: Configuration Hardening Maturity 1 Activity On the first maturity level, you&amp;rsquo;ve recognized the importancy of configuration hardening of third party components across the full stack, defined the relevant scope for this activity and have also provably taken the first steps in this activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operational Management</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/operations/o-operational-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/operations/o-operational-management/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Operational Management practice focuses on activities to ensure security is maintained throughout operational support functions. Although these functions are not performed directly by an application, the overall security of the application and its data is dependent on their proper performance. All of the protections built into an application can be rendered irrelevant by deploying the application on an unsupported operating system with unpatched vulnerabilities, or failing to store backup media securely.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>