<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on OWASP SAMM</title>
    <link>https://owaspsamm.org/business_functions/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on OWASP SAMM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owaspsamm.org/business_functions/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Threat Assessment</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/design/d-threat-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/design/d-threat-assessment/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Threat Assessment (TA) practise is focused on accurately identifying and understanding potential attacks upon an organisation&amp;rsquo;s software in order to better understand the risks and facilitate risk management. Indeed, software assurance is all about identifying risks in applications and treating them accordingly.
Risks to an application can be relative to the business of the application (think about business logic attacks) or to the technical setup of the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Requirements</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/design/d-security-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/design/d-security-requirements/</guid>
      <description>This security practice focuses on security requirements that are important in the context of secure software. A first type of requirements deals with typical software-related requirements, to specify concrete objectives and expectations to protect the service and data that form part of the application. A second type of requirements deals with requirements that are relative to supplier companies that are part of the development context of the application, in particular for outsourced development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Architecture</title>
      <link>https://owaspsamm.org/core/design/d-security-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owaspsamm.org/core/design/d-security-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Overview     A: Secure Architecture Design B: Technology Management     Maturity 1 - Insert consideration of proactive security guidance into the software design process. Use basic security principles Elicit technologies, frameworks and integrations within the overall solution   Maturity 2 - Direct the software design process toward known secure services and secure-by-default designs. Establish common design patterns and security solutions Standardize technologies and frameworks to be used throughout the different applications   Maturity 3 - Formally control the software design process and validate utilization of secure components.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>